[{"id": "590679b0ff9c0647b50a8050", "question": "On January 1, 2016, which Canadian province became the first one to allow the testing of self-driving vehicles on public roads?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdff6961cf6db9ac4808cef", "question": "What is the world\u2019s largest plateau?", "answer": "Tibetan Plateau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53f", "question": "What letter is least used in the English language?", "answer": "Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977d", "question": "The Hobbit Samwise Gamgee was played by whom in Lord of the Rings?", "answer": "Sean Astin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbe7d003d27d341092bcf", "question": "Which South American city is laid out in the shape of a puma?", "answer": "Cusco, Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d30", "question": "What novel is Aldous Huxley's fifth novel?", "answer": "A Brave New World", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919b", "question": "Who finds E.T.?", "answer": "Elliot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a347", "question": "What decade did the TV special \"It's the Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown\" come out in?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338921", "question": "Although he is from hell, what symbol does Spawn cling to?", "answer": "A cross", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c927", "question": "How many feet are there in a nautical mile?", "answer": "6,076", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339135", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Hamlet\", who is the daughter of Polonius?", "answer": "Ophelia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a838", "question": "What Ivy League university is located in Ithaca, NY?", "answer": "Cornell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43b", "question": "What year did Albert Einstein die?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecda56ec223966ae8f88e8", "question": "What was the first movie for which the cost of obtaining rights to the soundtrack outweighed all other production costs?", "answer": "Clerks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8f", "question": "Who composed the opera \"A Village Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "Frederick Delius", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390cd", "question": "Which is Shakespeare's shortest play?", "answer": "The Comedy of Errors", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca9", "question": "What drink is made from fermented honey, yeast and water?", "answer": "Mead", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e95017ccba3ffe45786db", "question": "Which computer scientist was largely responsible for the design of \"FLOW-MATIC\", the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "Grace Hopper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b227", "question": "What city was Medgar Evens killed in?", "answer": "Jackson, Mississippi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2a", "question": "Who invented the vacuum flask?", "answer": "James Dewar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe937c36bd93ce3a4e5f676", "question": "Gamophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Marriage and commitment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89a", "question": "In the card game Blackjack, what two values does the Ace have?", "answer": "1 and 11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015deebfe83fe1f2a824b74", "question": "What countries were involved in the Wars of the Three Kingdoms?", "answer": "England, Ireland, and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1f", "question": "Who was the first person to receive an artificial heart implant?", "answer": "Barney Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d47071f8e329de4f877891", "question": "What year was cricketer Phil Tufnell born?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec5", "question": "In what year was the hit game \"Minecraft\" released?", "answer": "2009", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baae", "question": "What company helped the US Army Corps of Engineers develop the \"walkie-talkie\" in the early 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Motorola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65e0a1f3c0ead6880d625", "question": "What natural disaster struck the American Midwest in 1930?", "answer": "The Dust Bowl", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c2", "question": "What is the name for a baby alligator?", "answer": "Hatchling", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce5", "question": "What team lost the pennant in 1908 thanks to \"Merkle's boner\"?", "answer": "The New York Giants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd5b8ec223966ae8f88d1", "question": "The traditional Wimbledon colors are green, and what?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062a24c9d816e292245c14", "question": "Who painted \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Salvador Dal\u00ed -- \"The Persistence of Memory,\" aka \"The Melting Watches,\" is one of Dali's most recognizable works.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba2", "question": "Who wrote the children's novel \"Swallows and Amazons\"?", "answer": "Arthur Ransome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fc", "question": "Which country were the 2016 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edd", "question": "What position was first held by John Adams?", "answer": "US Vice President", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd6bbe347d002c297e4bc", "question": "Morten Harket is the lead singer of which band?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a433", "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b366", "question": "What nationality was the explorer Vitus Bering?", "answer": "Danish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e50", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Black Caesar\"?", "answer": "Fred Williamson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12d0de39efa6330e0fec9", "question": "How long is the Panama Canal?", "answer": "51 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339734", "question": "How many frames fit into 1 foot of movie film?", "answer": "16", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636d9f967692ea851899af", "question": "The surface of what is typically 70% water and 10% ice?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a60d", "question": "Which country has the world's largest protected nature reserve?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad4", "question": "From 1956 to 1965, Bill Cullen hosted the original version of what TV game show?", "answer": "The Price is Right", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ac", "question": "Blues legend McKinley Morganfield was better known by what name?", "answer": "Muddy Waters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ca04877e98cb97778a00", "question": "What is the capital of the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Road Town", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83c", "question": "How many zeroes are there in a trillion?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72b", "question": "The Ohio River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b54e01dd7bf43be5e7ce", "question": "What are Bic pens named after?", "answer": "A version of the founder's name", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339285", "question": "The alliance \"Chilltown\" consists of what two players?", "answer": "Dr. Will and Mike Boogie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f45", "question": "What sheriff's alter ego was the masked \"El Kabong\"?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c071", "question": "What is the name of the kneeling cushions in churches?", "answer": "Hassock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40a", "question": "Which tree is the only nut-bearer native to North America?", "answer": "Pecan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae22", "question": "What are the four permanent, non-US members of the United Nations Security Council?", "answer": "China, France, Russia, United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a21b", "question": "Craig Phillips was the first winner of the UK version of which TV reality show?", "answer": "Big Brother", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf68", "question": "How many days are there in a leap year?", "answer": "366", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f84", "question": "What is the name of the son of the witch Sycorax?", "answer": "Caliban in The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc6", "question": "What was the name of the ship that Jason & his Argonauts sail in?", "answer": "Argo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943b", "question": "What brand of motorcycle does Tom Cruise ride in the 1986 movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Kawasaki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f3058515aa2bc17b61b2ad6", "question": "Who wrote the operas \"The Magic Flute\" and \"The Marriage of Figaro\"?", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c641", "question": "What is a group of lions called?", "answer": " A pride", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338962", "question": "What is the first name of Agatha Christie's sleuth Miss Marple?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bba", "question": "Who went down to Hades to rescue his wife Eurydice?", "answer": "Orpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07a", "question": "The Civil War battle called Manassas by the South, was called what by the North?", "answer": "Bull Run", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b174555bb2d29f81593b700", "question": "Lou Gramm was a member of which British-American rock band?", "answer": "Foreigner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4a09ff048f679a45abc0", "question": "What is a plant with no internal system of tube like structures called?", "answer": "Nonvascular Plant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96c8623c87fd04dd15e26", "question": "Which U.S. president received offers to play in the NFL?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b9", "question": "What instrument did Don Henley play as a member of Eagles?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab1c", "question": "Where are the Guiana Highlands located?", "answer": "Northeastern South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64f", "question": "What is the top layer of the Earth called?", "answer": "The Crust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339848", "question": "What comedian was nickname \"Mr. Television\"?", "answer": "Milton Berle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c193", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a3", "question": "Who created James Bond?", "answer": "Ian Fleming", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c9", "question": "What New York landmark stands in size 879 sandals?", "answer": "The Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe655aaae7e414034b5aeb7", "question": "Which ancient wonder was burned down by a fame-seeking arsonist?", "answer": "Temple of Artemis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3867c73aa70ea0b70ad0", "question": "Which US state gets its name from a made-up word?", "answer": " Idaho (Mining lobbyist George M. Willing told Congress \"Idaho\" was a Native American phrase for \"gem of the mountains\". He made it up.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae2", "question": "Which British prime minister was awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafb", "question": "The fear of punishment is known as what?", "answer": "Poinephobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339308", "question": "In the 1987 movie \"Fatal Attraction\", what animal did the obsessed woman cook on the stove?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d7", "question": "What Canadian city was Mill Street beer originally brewed in?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede2026ce05a3942286dca", "question": "Which Pink Floyd album features Easter Island statues on the cover?", "answer": "\"Division Bell\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d08241a1c922dd1ac64c0", "question": "Ulaanbaatar is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f6", "question": "What is the usual age for a Jewish boy to celebrate his bar mitzvah?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e0", "question": "Where are you, if you landed at Lindberg Airport?", "answer": "San Diego", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a5527e3e1c6f9840ba3196", "question": "The telephone country code 82 would connect you with which country?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a717", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Wolverine State\"?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08e", "question": "Who portrayed Han Solo in the Star Wars film series?", "answer": "Harrison Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a426", "question": "In which country would you find St. Basil's cathedral?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338950", "question": "What Mozart opera focuses on fiancee swapping as its theme?", "answer": "Cosi fan tutte", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba67", "question": "In religion, Siddh&#257;rtha Gautama was better known as whom?", "answer": "Buddha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab64", "question": "From what country did the US buy the Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7fd", "question": "What are the four \"C\" used to evaluate the value and quality of a diamond?", "answer": "Carat, cut, clarity and color", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb36", "question": "What is the three letter name of the red, brimless hat which originated in Morocco?", "answer": "Fez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d19", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Sarkisian LaPiere?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a6", "question": "In what city do The Simpsons live?", "answer": "Springfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddfc36ce05a3942286db2", "question": "What major global event serves as the background setting for the film \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "The Great Depression", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa4e36ce05a3942286eb8", "question": "In the film \"Ghostbusters,\" what is the occupation of Louis Tully?", "answer": "Accountant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949b", "question": "What actor replaced Michael J. Fox as the deputy mayor on the TV show \"Spin City\"?", "answer": "Charlie Sheen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015dfcefe83fe1f2a824b80", "question": "What was invented by Chinese astronomer and mathematician Chang Heng in 132 A.D.?", "answer": "The first seismograph", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d51", "question": "Author Margaret Atwood is a graduate of which Canadian University?", "answer": "University of Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a329", "question": "Who played the role of Elaine in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Annette O'Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929d", "question": "In \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\", what candy did Willy Wonka create for children who had very little money?", "answer": "The Everlasting Gobstopper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c5d49076251badbead2", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "The term \"motel\" originated with the\u00a0Milestone Mo-Tel, which was constructed in 1925 by Arthur Heineman.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392cd", "question": "What 2001 thriller starred Halle Berry, John Travolta, and Hugh Jackman?", "answer": "Swordfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac8", "question": "What chemical element's atomic number is 50?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3c", "question": "During what decade did the Charleston become the dance craze?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990f901fa5fdd6dd25324f3", "question": "Who sang a cover of \"Never Can Say Goodbye\" in 1974?", "answer": "Gloria Gaynor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf08", "question": "What crime has a person committed if they have been convicted of Regicide?", "answer": "They have killed the King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20f5331a458464a93c431", "question": "Who was Huck's Black friend in the novel \"The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn\"?", "answer": "Jim", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5e", "question": "For what does the \"F.\" stand in the name F. Lee Bailey?", "answer": "Francis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafa", "question": "Poinephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Punishment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a9", "question": "What popular brand of soup was introduced in 1897?", "answer": "Campbell's Soup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d0d", "question": "Uriah Heep was a character in what Charles Dickens novel?", "answer": "David Copperfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133979d", "question": "What movie put Queen's 1976 hit \"Bohemian Rhapsody\" back on the charts in 1992?", "answer": "Wayne's World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339895", "question": "The line \"Greed, for a lack of better word, is good!\" can be heard in what movie?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ea", "question": "Which is the highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd1", "question": "What TV show did \"Mork and Mindy\" spin off from?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7a1cff048f679a45abe7", "question": "What is the scientific term for peeling skin?", "answer": "Desquamation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66216a5bfecdd737e0841", "question": "Who was on the first cover of \"Rolling Stone\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c268", "question": "What is the common name for hydrogen hydroxide?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339348", "question": "What was Ward Cleaver's occupation on the TV show \"Leave it to Beaver\"?", "answer": "Accountant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909caddbb53d1af658864d3", "question": "What ABC Original Movie, starring Jenny McCarthy, air on December 10, 2006?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600240d14be4723ccac22169", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dances with Wolves\"?", "answer": "Michael Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbae", "question": "What term for a Bigfoot creature comes from the Salish Indian word meaning \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7b", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f4a5cee580c7f8fd1e59", "question": "What was the name of the commission that investigated the assassination of John F. Kennedy?", "answer": "Warren Commission", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65c641f3c0ead6880d614", "question": "Before starting Wendy's, what fast food franchise did Dave Thomas work for?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba3c0874c93a3298b2140", "question": "What was the full name of Queen Elizabeth The Queen Mother", "answer": "Elizabeth Angela Marguerite Bowes-Lyon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "593c4ba4b8198b9a2b077965", "question": "Who is Scarlett's first husband who died in the Civil War in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Charles Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b0", "question": "Which European country is divided into areas called Cantons?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b941", "question": "What 4 tournaments make up golf's Grand Slam for men?", "answer": "Masters, PGA, U.S. & British Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70c", "question": "In the Christmas song, The Holly and The Ivy which one bears the crown?", "answer": "The holly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963e", "question": "How is film star Marion Morrison better known?", "answer": "John Wayne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f839fe83fe1f2a824c2a", "question": "The \"St. Valentine's Day Massacre\" was perpetrated by which historical figure?", "answer": "Al Capone ordered the murders on February 14, 1929, but the primary target got away.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a5d020565ad31a57c7d1", "question": "Seeds for what fruit were found in King Tut\u2019s tomb?", "answer": "Watermelon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7f", "question": "Who was the first left-hander to serve two terms as US president?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ec0e08d98002fdd633b6", "question": "Which singer wrote the autobiography \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d1", "question": "In 2004, Norodom Sihanouk renounced the throne of what Asian country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92d", "question": "Where is the Swimming Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Fort Lauderdale, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7ecafb24f84e0b9f9ffe9", "question": "What is a sphygmomanometer used to measure?", "answer": "Blood pressure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6a", "question": "In what year did Cassius Clay win an Olympic gold medal for boxing in the light heavyweight division?", "answer": "1960", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72caf2d0874f1a5e2d1c1f", "question": "What animal has the most teeth?", "answer": "Snails", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904a471cf93664eb10486c3", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Katchoo\u2019s full name?", "answer": "Katina Marie Choovanski", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c412", "question": "What bird has the biggest eyes of any land animal?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef61876ce05a3942286e53", "question": "Which Hall of Fame British rocker is also an astrophysicist?", "answer": "Brian May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c5", "question": "The term \"black market\" was first used during which war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9f", "question": "Tashkent is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f56", "question": "What did the Elf Hermy want to be in the movie \"Rudolph, the Red-Nosed Reindeer\"?", "answer": "Dentist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6691ea5bfecdd737e0877", "question": "What is the main alcohol in a Moscow Mule?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69fbb20565ad31a57c78f", "question": "What US founding father also founded the University of Pennsylvania?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067ca2ff9c0647b50a806e", "question": "What virtual reality set was launched in March, 2016?", "answer": "Occulus Rift", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59b", "question": "What is the granular substance that bees collect called?", "answer": "Pollen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f2", "question": "A light aircraft without an engine is called a what?", "answer": "Glider or a sailplane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e95237ccba3ffe45786dc", "question": "Who sang the theme song for the TV show \"The Love Boat\"?", "answer": "Jack Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd59", "question": "The Vezina Trophy is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Hockey goaltending", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2a", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Lagaan\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e9", "question": "What was the name of the law firm featured in the TV series \"The Practice\"?", "answer": "Robert Donnell and Associates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1c", "question": "How many battleships were sunk during the attack of Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c0", "question": "What is the more common name for Scapula?", "answer": "Shoulder blade", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad2", "question": "Which European city is nicknamed \"The Eternal City\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b88001dd7bf43be5e7eb", "question": "What is a group of snails referred to as?", "answer": "A walk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43d", "question": "What was George Hepplewhite's profession?", "answer": "Furniture maker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdc66e347d002c297e4e7", "question": "Which year was the film \"Shanghai Surprise\", starring Madonna and Sean Penn, released in?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339941", "question": "Who had Top 10 hits in the 1950\u2019s with \"Ain\u2019t That a Shame\" and \"Blueberry Hill\"?", "answer": "Fats Domino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c4d3877e98cb977789a7", "question": "What is the only country with coasts on the Persian Gulf and the Caspian Sea?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a2", "question": "What was the longest-running musical on Broadway during the 20th century?", "answer": "Cats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25a53b63e5727cf5a4852", "question": "Who sang the songs \"Bump n' Grind\" and \"She's Got That Vibe\"?", "answer": "R Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb35b4f2627b8fe95581beb", "question": "In ABC's \"Once Upon a Time\" what character was played by Colin O' Donoghue?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012188763c99d48cd169af4", "question": "What flavor is Cointreau?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab97", "question": "Which sea separates Greece from Asia Minor?", "answer": "Aegean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6557dae7e414034b5aeb2", "question": "What was the precursor to electric lights on a Christmas tree?", "answer": "Candles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c0c1877e98cb9777896e", "question": "What is the least populated continguous U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e5", "question": "What nationality was writer Arthur C. Clarke?", "answer": "British", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd8a8e347d002c297e4c8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Icarus' father?", "answer": "Daedalus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e6", "question": "What name is given to the ancient Christian and Jewish underground burial chambers in and around Rome?", "answer": "Catacombs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec234a8dc25ca9e12ef62f", "question": "By what name is \"Calcium oxide\" more commonly known?", "answer": "Quicklime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b497649076251badbeaae", "question": "Where in the world was Richard Nixon when he delivered his infamous \"I am not a crook\" speech?", "answer": "Disney World (Orlando, Florida)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897d", "question": "What was Long John Silver's parrot Captain Flint favorite phrase?", "answer": "Pieces of eight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338faa", "question": "Which author wrote \"If I Forget Thee, Jerusalem\"?", "answer": "William Faulkner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d11", "question": "In \"The Farmer in the Dell\", what stands alone?", "answer": "The cheese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e940c7ccba3ffe45786cd", "question": "What year did Buddy Holly die in a plane crash?", "answer": "1959", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae3", "question": "First minted in 2000, whose likeness was on the face-side of the US dollar coin?", "answer": "Sacagawea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f71efa9e54d890926f6e7", "question": "What was the original name of Austin, the capital of Texas?", "answer": "Waterloo -- It was renamed after Texas leader Stephen F. Austin in 1839.  It became the state capital in 1845.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d7", "question": "Which famous BBC presenter goes by the name of Jezza?", "answer": "Jeremy Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa6", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Red and the Green\"?", "answer": "Iris Murdoch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b600", "question": "What US state was the home of General Motors' original \"Saturn\" automobile plant?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339672", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Seymour Skinner's real name?", "answer": "Armin Tamzarian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d0", "question": "Which US president on Mount Rushmore has a mustache?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bb", "question": "What former Governor of Pennsylvania became the first Secretary of Homeland Security in 2003?", "answer": "Tom Ridge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a98d", "question": "What city named its airport after Lester Pearson?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a6a190aac110e416707f", "question": "Who created the Lipton tea brand?", "answer": "Thomas Lipton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d86", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Manhunter\" based on?", "answer": "Red Dragon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388dc", "question": "As punishment for not appreciating Apollo's music, King Midas's ears were transformed into the ears of what animal?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b959", "question": "What is the name of the musical instrument which is a combination of two small drums, one bahina and the other dahina?", "answer": "Tabla", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b491e49076251badbeaac", "question": "Who said, \"In the future, everyone will be world-famous for 15 minutes\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol -- There is debate as to whether the phrase is his word, but branded it and put in pamphlet in 1968.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590681e5ff9c0647b50a8098", "question": "What fictional town is the Netflix series \"Stranger Things\" based in?", "answer": "Hawkins, Indiana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5724c73aa70ea0b70b31", "question": "The May Day Run, held annually in England, involves thousands of what?", "answer": "Motorbikes taking the 55-mile trek from Locksbottom to Hastings.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e95527ccba3ffe45786de", "question": "Malagasy is the native language of which country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22d", "question": "What country are eclairs said to have originated from?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba8", "question": "Which US state has Cheyenne as its capital city?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acef", "question": "What was U.S. President Wilson's first name?", "answer": "Thomas (Woodrow was his middle name)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1a", "question": "What 1977 novel ends with Milkman Dead learning to fly?", "answer": "Song of Solomon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b142", "question": "What American won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2007?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc95", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Peloton\"?", "answer": "Cycling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd54fec223966ae8f88cf", "question": "What TV show won the most Emmys in 2018?", "answer": "The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66fe552a821ff76ae8b20", "question": "What extreme sport is forbidden by law in Louisiana?", "answer": "To try and wrestle a bear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a61902ebb971c1417fb88", "question": "How many hurdles are there in a 400 metres hurdle race?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f4", "question": "What chess piece has a horse's head?", "answer": "Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe775dbeec85e375820b312", "question": "Where are the Baalbek Roman ruins located?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13f", "question": "\"Safety Dance\" was a hit for which band?", "answer": "Men Without Hats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c9", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"I've said it before and I'll say it again: Democracy simply doesn't work.\"?", "answer": "Kent Brockman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339266", "question": "What is baby Superman called on the planet Krypton?", "answer": "Kal-El", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339670", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's water park?", "answer": "Mount Splashmore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a14acad1ec93f27df775", "question": "In a Cortado, what is the main purpose of the milk?", "answer": "To reduce the acidity of the coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1c", "question": "In 1992, which US state began offering tourist info at 1-800-33-GUMBO?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca78", "question": "\"Fagus\" is the Latin name of what type of tree?", "answer": "Beech", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7e", "question": "What is the last name of Mel Gibson's character in the \"Lethal Weapon\" films?", "answer": "Riggs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8d68ec223966ae8f8853", "question": "Which American situation comedy starred an actress who was of direct Maltese descent?", "answer": "\"Boy Meets World\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a9", "question": "Who had the job of eliminating maverick androids?", "answer": "Blade runners", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28b", "question": "Who is the lead singer of Metallica?", "answer": "James Hetfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee1", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for Tom Clancy's CIA agent in the Kremlin?", "answer": "The Cardinal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3662ff048f679a45ab0c", "question": "\"Squab\" is a name given to the young of which bird?", "answer": "Pigeon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c792", "question": "Cheetahs are native to what two continents?", "answer": "Africa and Asia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f565ef33a95c66dc4fe75c", "question": "Bismarck is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c7", "question": "What Briton with an American wife was the governor of the Bahamas during World War II?", "answer": "King Edward VIII", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc89", "question": "What NHL team's theme music is Aram Khachaturian's most famous composition?", "answer": "The Buffalo Sabres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febbc8b7e83c707845b214d", "question": "In what round of the NFL draft was quarterback Tom Brady selected in?", "answer": "Brady was the 199th pick in the sixth round of the 2000 NFL draft.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77ceaf24f0f7a362efd548", "question": "The CN Tower is in which Canadian city?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc4206ce05a3942286f2d", "question": "What is the name of the ramrod in the television series \"Rawhide\"?", "answer": "Rowdy Yates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa64", "question": "Which continent is Mauritania a part of?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067a6eff9c0647b50a8059", "question": "In 2016, which vessel became the first solar-powered aircraft to circumnavigate the Earth?", "answer": "Solar Impulse 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600781c2bd51d85e222ab64f", "question": "How many versions of The Scream did Edvard Munch create?", "answer": "There are\u00a0five separate versions of the work - four paintings and a lithograph stone from which as many as 45 prints were made.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c187", "question": "What democratic senator that is a cousin of actress/comedian Amy Schumer?", "answer": "Charles \"Chuck\" Schumer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f5", "question": "Where does Yogi Bear live?", "answer": "Jellystone National Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19b", "question": "What was the name of the official 1972 Summer Olympics mascot?", "answer": "Waldi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2d", "question": "Someone who raises false alarms is said to cry what?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cdfe7bd84c0ea43ad432", "question": "Which city is directly northwest of Windsor, Ontario?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922e", "question": "Who stars in the semi-autobiographical movie \"Purple Rain\"?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf6", "question": "The infamous Pez dispenser was first patented in what year?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e0", "question": "Which US state is home to both the highest and lowest points in the contiguous 48 US states?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13e", "question": "In the first Punic War, Rome and Carthage fought over possession of what Mediterranean island?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b8", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Maurice \"Rocket\" Richard born?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03c", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Peter started a church worshipping which \"Happy Days\" character?", "answer": "The Fonz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068023ff9c0647b50a808a", "question": "Which British actor played the role of Spider-Man in the 2016 film \"Captain America: Civil War\"?", "answer": "Tom Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd69fcd6c0f9723ab15cb2f", "question": "What was the first book sold on Amazon?", "answer": "\"Fluid Concepts And Creative Analogies\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339adc", "question": "What was the name of the middle Tanner daughter on \"Full House\"?", "answer": "Stephanie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1b", "question": "Who employs Alfred Pennyworth as a butler?", "answer": "Bruce Wayne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf7", "question": "The feet of the infamous Pez dispenser were not added until what year?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a233", "question": "What famous actor was slated to play the alien in the 1987 film \"Predator\" but was replaced?", "answer": "Jean-Claude Van Damme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c3049076251badbeacf", "question": "Which unique pet did Calvin Coolidge have during his presidency?", "answer": "Raccoon -- Named Rachel, she might be the most well known pet.  She walked around on a leash and was the master of mischief.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af06", "question": "President Gerald Ford was a member of which political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b86", "question": "In the comic strip Peanuts, what color is Woodstock?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6b28dfb6c85e9e634ff3f", "question": "Which years did Henry VI reign England?", "answer": "1422 to 1461 and 1470 to 1471", "category": "history"}]